apply2jobs.com 2004-12-08

# VirtualEdge

We respect your privacy. This is why we have taken the time to disclose our information collection practices and our privacy statement. VirtualEdge strives to collect and use personally identifiable information ("PII") in a manner consistent with the laws of the countries in which we operate. Please take the time to review this document. This statement discloses: 

  1. VirtualEdge.com Privacy Statement as it applies to the use of VirtualEdge.com; 
  2. Privacy Statement relevant to information received, maintained or processed by VirtualEdge as an Application Service Provider ("ASP") through usage of E*TRACK System™ software; 
  3. Standard Privacy Practices; 
  4. TRUSTe Privacy Program Participation. 

**VirtualEdge.com Privacy Statement**

This statement applies to the usage of VirtualEdge.com. VirtualEdge is the sole owner of the information collected on this site. We will not sell, share, or rent this information to others in ways different from what is disclosed in this statement. 

We collect information for the following purpose(s): 

  * Using personal information obtained from users, including but not limited to name, mailing address, and email address to contact user in regard to interest in VirtualEdge products and services. We may use contact information collected through the White Paper collection form as a sales lead generator. 
  * Periodically send our visitor and/or customers email newsletters with information about our products and services. 
  * Employment consideration with VirtualEdge Corporation through the use of E*TRACK. 
  * Completing or supporting an activity. 
  * Tailoring the website and navigation for visitors. 
  * Log Files - VirtualEdge uses IP addresses, referring urls, date and time stamp to analyze trends, administer the site, track user's movement, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. VirtualEdge will only associate any of this information with an individual user to support the successful use of our applications. 
  * Cookies - We strive to make a user's experience at VirtualEdge.com easy and meaningful. When a user visits our site, our Web server sends a cookie to the user's computer. Cookies are files that Web browsers place in a computer's hard drive or memory. Standing alone, cookies do not identify a user personally. They merely recognize a user's browser. Unless a user chooses to identify themselves to VirtualEdge.com, either by responding to a advertisement or subscribing to a newsletter they remain anonymous. Cookies come in two types: session and persistent-based. Session cookies exist in a computer's memory only during an online session. They disappear from a user's computer when they close their browser software or turn off their computer. Persistent cookies remain on a user's computer after a user has closed their browser or turned off their computer. They include such information as a unique identifier for a user's browser. 

VirtualEdge.com uses session cookies containing encrypted information to allow the system to uniquely identify a user while supplying information required to receive newsletters or download white papers. This information allows VirtualEdge.com to process online transactions and requests. Users who disable their Web browsers' ability to accept cookies will not be able to successfully use our site. 

VirtualEdge requires cookies only to store information required to maintain session management. 

  * Provide users who no longer wish to receive email communications with ability to opt-out of receiving email. 

VirtualEdge.com may contain links to other sites. Please be advised that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of other sites. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by VirtualEdge.com. 

We allow our visitors access to all collected information. If a user no longer desires to receive our newsletters or collected information has changed, we provide a way to correct, update or delete/deactivate a user's PII. This can be done by contacting VirtualEdge Privacy Statement Support at Privacy@VirtualEdge.com or unsubscribing at VirtualEdge.com. 

**ASP Privacy Statement**  
Our ASP Privacy Statement applies strictly to the transmission of personally identifiable information ("PII") received by VirtualEdge Corporation through its hosted workforce acquisition software (E*TRACK System™), supplied directly by our customers or by the visitors of our customer career centers for employment consideration. Visitors to VirtualEdge.com should refer to the VirtualEdge.com Privacy Statement. 

VirtualEdge Corporation abides by the EU Safe Harbor framework as set forth by the Department of Commerce regarding collection, use, and retention of data from the European Union. VirtualEdge operates as a data processor for our E*TRACK customers. Our customers are the controllers of the data collected and maintained. Users involved in recruiting activities supported by E*TRACK communicate directly with our customers, not VirtualEdge. VirtualEdge provides its customers with the option to disclose their relationship with us by providing notice to their users of E*TRACK. VirtualEdge only maintains the information our customers have asked us to process related to the recruitment process. 

This ASP Privacy Statement does not reflect the privacy practices of our customers and VirtualEdge is not responsible for its customers' privacy policies or practices. VirtualEdge does not review, comment upon or monitor its customers' compliance with their respective privacy policies, nor does VirtualEdge review its customer instructions to determine whether they are in compliance with or conflict with the terms of a customer's published privacy policy. 

_Use of Information_  
As an ASP, VirtualEdge operates as a data processor for our customers. Our customers are the data collectors and controllers of the data. Users involved in recruiting activities supported by E*TRACK communicate directly with our customers, not VirtualEdge. 

VirtualEdge maintains only the information our customers have requested we process as required by their recruitment process. It is the VirtualEdge customers' responsibility to ensure that the data they collect can be legally collected in the country of origin. The VirtualEdge customer is responsible for providing its employees and employment candidates the appropriate level of notification that PII is being collected and maintained. VirtualEdge provides its customers with the option to disclose notification of collection and maintenance of PII to employment candidates using E*TRACK. 

_Onward Transfer_  
VirtualEdge may engage other companies and agents to perform tasks on behalf of VirtualEdge (i.e., resume processing). If VirtualEdge discloses information of our customers to a third party that is acting as our agent or on our behalf, VirtualEdge will make certain that the third party has agreed to abide by this policy as well as VirtualEdge data security guidelines, or can otherwise assure satisfactory protection of PII. Satisfactory protection may be achieved by entering into written agreements with third parties requiring third parties to provide, minimally, the same level of privacy protection as is required by this policy and VirtualEdge data security guidelines. 

_Access to Collected Information_  
As an ASP, VirtualEdge collects PII on behalf of another company. To request access to or correction of this information, please contact the company to which you provided it. E*TRACK provides our customers access to all of the information processed on their behalf and provides for the processing of any requested corrections. 

**Standard Privacy Practices**

_Security_  
VirtualEdge is committed to the highest level of security for the information we process and store. To prevent unauthorized access or disclosure and to ensure the appropriate use of information, we have implemented physical, logical, and administrative procedures to protect and secure the information we process and maintain. 

While we use encryption and firewall technology to protect sensitive information online, we also do everything in our power to protect user-information off-line. All of the information collected is restricted. Only employees who need the information to perform a specific job are granted access to PII. All VirtualEdge employees are kept up-to-date on our security and privacy practices. Every quarter, as well as any time new policies are added, our employees are notified and/or reminded about the importance we place on privacy, and what they can do to ensure information collected is protected. 

_Onward Transfer_  
VirtualEdge may engage other companies and agents to perform tasks on behalf of VirtualEdge (i.e., resume processing). If VirtualEdge discloses information of our customers to a third party that is acting as our agent or on our behalf, VirtualEdge will make certain that the third party has agreed to abide by this policy as well as VirtualEdge data security guidelines, or can otherwise assure satisfactory protection of PII. Satisfactory protection may be achieved by entering into written agreements with third parties requiring third parties to provide, minimally, the same level of privacy protection as is required by this policy and VirtualEdge data security guidelines. 

_Notification of Change_   
If we decide to change our privacy statement, we will post those changes on our site so our users are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under circumstances, if any, we disclose it. If at any point we decide to use PII in a manner materially different from that stated at the time it was collected, we will notify users by way of a prominent notice for 30 days. Users will have a choice as to whether or not we use their information in this different manner. We will use information in accordance with the privacy policy under which the information was collected. 

_Disclaimer_  
We may disclose PII when required by law or in the good faith belief that disclosure is required to comply with legal mandate, enforce the terms of usage of VirtualEdge.com, or to protect the rights, property, or personal safety of VirtualEdge, users of E*TRACK and the public. In the event of an inadvertent disclosure of information, VirtualEdge will take all commercially reasonable steps to limit and remedy the disclosure. However, we cannot guarantee that unauthorized third parties will never be able to defeat implemented safeguards or use your PII for improper purposes.

**TRUSTe Privacy Program**

VirtualEdge Corporation is a licensee of the TRUSTe Privacy Program. TRUSTe is an independent, non-profit organization whose mission is to enable individuals and organizations to establish trusting relationships based on respect for personal identity and information by promoting the use of fair information practices. TRUSTe coverage of this privacy statement includes the site www.virtualedge.com. Because we want to demonstrate our commitment to our users' privacy, we have agreed to disclose our privacy practices and have them reviewed for compliance by TRUSTe. 

We participate in the EU Safe Harbor Privacy Framework as set forth by the United States Department of Commerce. As part of our participation in the safe harbor, we have agreed to TRUSTe dispute resolution for disputes relating to our compliance with the Safe Harbor Privacy Framework. If you have any complaints regarding our compliance with the Safe Harbor you should first contact us. If contacting us does not resolve your complaint, you may raise your complaint with TRUSTe by Internet at http://www.truste.org/consumers/watchdog_complaint.php, fax at 415-618-3421, or mail at Watchdog Complaints, TRUSTe, 685 Market Street, Suite 560, San Francisco, CA, USA 94105. If you are faxing or mailing TRUSTe to lodge a complaint, you must include the following information: the name of company, the alleged privacy violation, your contact information, and whether you would like the particulars of your complaint shared with the company. For information about TRUSTe or the operation of TRUSTe's dispute resolution process, see http://www.truste.org/consumers/watchdog_complaint.php or request this information from TRUSTe at any of the addresses listed above. The TRUSTe dispute resolution process shall be conducted in English.
